

Mehmet Deveci

Senior Frontend Developer/Full Stack Developer

I have been working with Vue.js, Nuxt.js, React, TypeScript, Next.js, PHP and Node.js, with a focus on crafting seamless user experiences, applications and infrastructures in the last 5 years in Berlin.

deveci2024@gmail.com

Berlin, Germany

+49 (178) 8980493

LinkedIn

https://www.volcode.org/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sdui GmbH Berlin, Germany

Senior Frontend Developer

February 2023 - July 2024

- Developed an event management system, boosted user interaction at least 20% through new editing features.
- Conceptualized and implemented video conference features for an app, improved user engagement with React.
- Wrote technical documentation that streamlined onboarding, reducing setup time by 30% on WebSockets.
- Guided junior developers through pair programming, enhancing their front-end skills and productivity.
- Developed a migration guide to help developers transition from Vue 2 to Vue 3 efficiently.
 See More

Homeday GmbH Berlin, Germany

Senior Frontend Developer

March 2020 - January 2023

- Migrated components and pages from PHP to Vue + Nuxt, improved page speeds up to 30%.*
- Built Infrastructure as Code with AWS and GitHub Actions at Homeday, reducing costs by 15%.*use case
- Optimized CI/CD pipelines by using Jest, Cypress, Vue Util Tests, and replacing unit tests with integration tests, reducing pipeline lifetime by 25%.
- Built, optimized, improved and maintained multiple apps with HTML5, CSS3, Javascript & Typescript, Vue, using BEM CSS, Storybook, Design System, NPM with a team of 30+ people in engineering.
- Mentored junior developers, enabling promotions within 8 months.
 See More

Turkish Radio Television Corporation

Istanbul, Turkey

Frontend Developer

March 2018 - March 2020

- Optimized election result pages, reducing load times by 25% for high volume of users during peak traffic.
- Built an embedded SVG-based map with Vue.js for Turkey's 2018 General Elections, handling 75k+ concurrent
 users with 100% uptime.
- Redesigned the internal image database, reducing search times by 50% and boosting editor efficiency.
- Developed and optimized a CMS editor, streamlining content creation for editors across the media platform.

Crabs Media - A Digital Web Agency

Istanbul, Turkey

Frontend Developer

May 2013 - May 2017

• Built 50+ interfaces with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and SQL (WordPress) for clients in diverse industries.

Fatih Municipality

Istanbul, Turkey

IT Support Internship

May 2012 - September 2012

SKILLS

Vue, Nuxt.js, TypeScript, React, Next.js, JavaScript, Node.js, Nest.js, WebSockets, PHP, Vite, Figma, Contentful, Stakeholder Management, Rest API, AWS, Cypress, Jest, Webpack, Git, Github, Docker, Postman, HTML, CSS, SCSS, LESS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Figma, Agile, Scrum, Kanban, BEM, MySQL, Laravel, Symfony, SQL, UI / UX

EDUCATION

Istanbul Arel University

Istanbul, Turkey

Associate's Degree on Computer Programming

2017

Inonu Technical High School

Istanbul, Turkey

Vocational Training on Information Technologies

2013

CERTIFICATES

Communicating with Emotional Intelligence, Interpersonal Communication, Writing a Tech Resume

DIVERSITY & INCLUSION

During my time at Homeday, I co-led a Diversity and Inclusion Taskforce, where I gained valuable experience in fostering inclusivity and collaboration within the workplace;

- Designed and implemented team-building strategies and OKRs.
- Delivered impactful Unconscious Bias Training, fostering awareness across teams.
- Planned and facilitated workshops, promoting inclusive and collaborative work culture.

LINKS

^{*} View recommendations from colleagues and managers on my LinkedIn profile.

^{*} Check my github profile I OR my github profile II

^{*} Watch mv introduction video in 2m

^{*} Check my portfolio project